Guide to the Duke University Libraries Collection of Haggadot, 1200-2003 (bulk1900-2003)
Duke University Libraries Collection of Haggadot 1200-2003 (bulk 1900-2003
- Location List Series, 1200-2003
  - United States Subseries, 1869-2002, (193 items)
    - Haggadah for the liberated lamb / [text editor, Roberta Kalechofsky; original text, by Roberta Kalechofsky], 1985., 26 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Passover Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah / compiled by Morris Silverman with contemporary readings, historical commentary, explanatory notes, and concise instructions, 1986., 26 cm. Illustrated.
    - San Diego women's Haggadah, 1986., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - A seder of the sisters of Sarah: a Holy Thursday and Passover feminist liturgy / created by Ronnie Levin and Diann Neu. Silver Spring, Md.: Women's Alliance for Theology, Ethics and Ritual, c1986, 1986., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - The new annotated Passover Haggadah = [Hagadah shel Pesah]: with an introduction, new English translation, expository notes, biblical and rabbinic sources, and instructions for the conduct of the Seder / by Nathan Goldberg, 1987., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - The tree [picture], 1987., 49 x 34 cm. Illustrated.
    - A song of David: a limited edition facsimile of the Moss Haggadah / [David Moss], 1987., 46 cm. Illuminated.
    - Chagall's Passover Haggadah / illustrated by Marc Chagall, 1987., 32 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Passover Haggadah: legends and customs / interpreted by Manachem Hacohen; drawings & design by Haim Ron, 1987., 31 cm. Illustrated.
    - Haggadah for the liberated lamb / [text editor, Roberta Kalechofsky; original text, by Roberta Kalechofsky], 1988., 27 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover/Haggadah., 1989., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah / brought to you by the coffees of Maxwell House, 1989., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - On wings of freedom: the Hillel Haggadah for the nights of Passover / edited and translated by Richard N. Levy, 1989., 24 cm. Text only.
      ...designed to serve nearly every sector of American Judaism, and contains virtually the entire traditional Haggadah text ..." -- Cover p. [4].
    - The kol dodi Haggadah: the complete Passover Haggadah with translation and the laws of the seder / by David Feinstein, 1990., 24 cm.
    - Abarbanel Haggadah: the Passover Haggadah with the commentary of Don Isaac Abarbanel / abridged and translated by Yisrael Isser Zvi Herczeg; edited by Shlomo Fox, 1990., 24 cm. Text only.
    - Haggadah of the chassidic masters / by Shalom Meir Wallach, 1990., 24 cm. Text only.
    - The Sinai Hagadah = [Hagadah shel Pesah, mekorah u-feshatah] / with a new translation and commentary based on Talmudic, midrashic and rabbinic sources by J. H. Sinason; including a detailed guide to the laws and customs of the Seder by A. Weiss, 1990., 22 cm. Text only.
    - The Moss Haggadah: a complete reproduction of the Haggadah written and illuminated by David Moss for Richard and Beatrice Levy, with the commentary of the artist, 1990., 36 cm. Illustrated.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah: bi-leshon ha-kodesh uvi-leshon Italyano = The Venice Haggadah, 1716: with Judeo-Italian translation, 1991., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1991., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - The commentators' seder = [Hagadah shel Pesah]: a companion volume to the Commentators' haggadah, including additional inspiring halachic insights and homilies / Yitzchak Sender, 1992., 24 cm. Text only.
    - [Hagadah shel Pesah] = A Passover haggadah / as commented upon by Elie Wiesel and illustrated by Mark Podwal; English commentaries edited by Marion Wiesel, 1993., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - The concise family Seder / prepared by Alfred J. Kolatch, 1993., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - A feast of history; Passover through the ages as a key to Jewish experience. With a new translation of the Haggadah for use at the Seder. [Photos. by David Harris], 1993., 25 cm. Illustrated.
    - Collector's Haggadah catalogue, 1695-present, 1994., 28 cm. Illustrated.
      Catalogue of Haggadot from 1695-1993 for collectors. All of the haggadot listed in the catalogue include short descriptions and were (in 1994) for sale by Irvin Ungar Historicana, a rare books dealer in California. Includes bibliographical references and indexes.
    - The open tomb: a new approach, Mark's Passover Haggadah ([ca.] 72 C.E.) / Karel Hanhart, 1995., 24 cm. Illustrated.
    - The scholar's Haggadah: Ashkenazic, Sephardic, and Oriental versions / with a historical-literary commentary by Heinrich Guggenheimer, 1995., 24 cm. Text only.
    - [Hagadah shel Pesah, mi-shi`bud li-ge'ulah] = From bondage to freedom: the Passover Haggadah: with a commentary illuminating the liberation of the spirit / by Abraham J. Twerski, with Hirsh Michel Chinn and Benzion Twerski, 1995., 25 cm. Text only.
    - The Peninim Haggadah = [Peninim Hagadah shel Pesah]: Haggadah text with English translation, thought-provoking insights and an informative question & answer section / by A. L. Scheinbaum, 1997., 24 cm. Text only.
    - Haggadah: a celebration of freedom / by Martha Shelley; with Hebrew translations by Ilana Brody, 1997., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - Lel she'elot: hagadah shel Pesah = A night of questions: a Passover haggadah / edited by Rabbi Joy Levitt, Rabbi Michael Strassfeld; illustrated by Jeffrey Schrier, 2000., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - Lel she'elot: hagadah shel Pesah = A night of questions: a Passover haggadah / edited by Rabbi Joy Levitt, Rabbi Michael Strassfeld; illustrated by Jeffrey Schrier, 2000., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - Let my people go: insights to Passover and the Haggadah / Jeffrey M. Cohen, 2002., 23 cm. Text only.
    - A haggadah for the second seder / adapted by the Kanof family, 199-?., 22 cm. Illustrated.
- Purpose List Series, 1200-2003
  Subdivided by the specific purpose for which each Haggadah was written, then arranged by date, then alphabetically. Most of the Haggadot were created for use at a Passover seder and thus are organized into the General Subseries. These Haggadot are generally traditional in content and are meant to be used by anyone. Other purpose subseries include Advertising, Children, Christian, Denominations (of Judaism), Facsimiles, Fundraising, Kibbutz, Parody, and Resource.
  - Advertising Subseries, 1889-1991, (16 items)
    Printed as marketing tools for specific companies and products. Includes the well-known Maxwell House editions (Haggadah Pam 12mo #28, Haggadah Pam #36, Haggadah Pam #54, E Pam 12mo #9683, E Pam #6620, Haggadah Pam 12mo #63).
    - Hagadah ve-seder shel Pesah = Form of service for the first two nights of the feast of Passover: with English translation, 1889., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah ve-Seder shel Pesah = form of service for the two first nights of the feast of Passover: with English translation, 190-?., 15 cm. Illustrated.
      Distributed by S.J. Gold, the South's Leading Kosher Delicatessen. Missing from library shelf.
    - Hagadah for Passover = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1949-1950., 17 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = Hagadah: Passover Seder Service, 1951., 14 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah for Passover = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1956-1957., 17 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 195-?., 18 x 25 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah for Passover = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1961-1962., 17 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1964., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover Haggadah = [Hagadah shel Pesah (romanized form)], 1965., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Haggadah for the American family: English service with directions / written by Martin Berkowitz, 1966., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Haggadah of Passover / translation: A. Regelson; illustration: S. Forst, 1968., 15 cm. Illustrated.
      Haggadah printed by the Carmel wine company. In addition to the traditional seder in both Hebrew and English, this Haggadah contains advertisements for the full line of Carmel wines, liquors and champagnes. At the back of the Haggadah are suggestions for how to serve Carmel's different products as well suggestions for Passover cocktails and how to cook with Carmel products.
    - Seder lel Pesah, 196-?., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover/Haggadah., 1989., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah / brought to you by the coffees of Maxwell House, 1989., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1991., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - The concise family Seder / prepared by Alfred J. Kolatch, 1993., 21 cm. Illustrated.
  - Children Subseries, 1948-1993, (13 items)
    Created specifically for children.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1942-1943., 27 cm. Illustrated.
    - [Hagadah li-yeladim] = The children's Haggadah / edited by Dr. A.M. Silbermann; illustrated by Ersin Singer; with a new translation in prose and verse by Mr. Isidore Wartski ... and Rev. Arthur Saul Super M.A.; and with a selection of Seder melodies, 1948., 30 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Haggadah for children / prepared by Jacob P. Rudin, 1952., 19 cm. Illustrated.
    - The model seder / prepared by Harry Nelson and Harry Malin, 1954., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      English and Hebrew. Changes made to make the seder more meaningful for the children.-- p. 3 Includes photographs of Jewish art and ritual objects.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1955., 28 cm. Illustrated.
    - Haggadah for young people / by Martha Marenof, 1957., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - A Haggadah for our time / edited and arranged by Rose Bernard; illustrated by Florence Sloat, 1962., 14 x 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1962., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah li-yeladim = The children's Haggadah / edited by A.M. Silbermann; illustrated by Erwin Singer; with a new translation in prose and verse by Isidore Wartski and Arthur Saul Super; and with a selection of Seder melodies, 1963., 30 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah li-yeladim = The children's Haggadah / edited by A.M. Silbermann; illustrated by Erwin Singer with a new translation in prose and verse by Isidore Wartski and Rev. Saul Super, 1972., 29 cm. Illustrated.
    - The animated Haggadah [videorecording], 1985., Video
    - Hagadah shel Leningrad = The Leningrad children's Haggadah = Leningradskaia agada / preface by Adin Steinzaltz; editor in chief I. Dvorkin, 1993., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - A haggadah for the second seder / adapted by the Kanof family, 199-?., 22 cm. Illustrated.
  - Christian Subseries, 1965-1995, (6 items)
    Reflect Christian's interest in conducting their own Passover seders. All date from the late 20th century.
    - The Gospel of Mark: the new Christian Jewish Passover Haggadah, 1965., 25 cm. Text only.
    - The Passover meal; a ritual for Christian homes, 1972., 17 cm. Illustrated.
    - A Christian Seder / by James G. Emerson, Jr, 1976., 23 cm. Text only.
    - Passover Seder: ritual and menu for an observance by Christians, 1984., 28 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover seder for christian families / Sam Mackintosh, 1984., 21 cm. Text only.
    - The open tomb: a new approach, Mark's Passover Haggadah ([ca.] 72 C.E.) / Karel Hanhart, 1995., 24 cm. Illustrated.
  - Denominations Subseries, 1757-2000, (28 items)
    Created specifically for a particular denomination of Judaism, including Reform Judaism (Haggadah #24), Sephardic Judaism (Haggadah #70), and Conservative Judaism (E #17469). Also includes Haggadot geared towards types of people who also happen to be Jews, such as the Haggadah for Lesbians (Divinity -- 296.45371 S589, L727, 1999) and a Haggadah for Vegetarians (E #18543).
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1757-1758., 24 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: Sephardic.
    - Sefer hamon hogeg, 1793-1794., 24 cm. Text only.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1795-1796., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - Seder agadah shel Pesah, 1805-1806., 19 cm. Illustrated.
    - Seder ha-hagadah shel Pesah, 1864., 32 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: Conservative.
    - The Union Haggadah: home service for the Passover / [edited by the Central Conference of American Rabbis], 1923., 20 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: Reform.
    - The new Haggadah for the Pesah Seder = Hagadah shel Pesah seder hadash / edited by Mordecai M. Kaplan, Eugene Kohn, and Ira Eisenstein for the Jewish Reconstructionist Foundation; illustrated by Leonard Weisgard, 1942., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: Reconstructionist.
    - Samaritan Haggada and Pessah Passover: Zevah korban ha-Pesah, 1958., 24 cm. Text only.
      Denomination: Samaritan.
      Contains the Samaritan ceremony for the Passover sacrifice. Text is written in the Paleo-Hebrew script still used by the Samaritan community, as well as the square Hebrew script.
    - The freedom seder; a new Haggadah for Passover, by Arthur I. Waskow, 1970., 19 cm. Illustrated.
      Freedom Seder was first used on April 4, 1969, the first anniversary of [Dr. Martin Luther] King's death and the third night of Passover by 300 €˜Jews for Urban Justice' and 100 Christians -The Shalom Seders, pg. 8.
    - A Passover Haggadah; the new Union Haggadah edited by Herbert Bronstein for the Central Conference of American Rabbis. Drawings by Leonard Baskin, 1974., 37 cm. Illustrated.
    - A Passover Haggadah; the new Union Haggadah edited by Herbert Bronstein for the Central Conference of American Rabbis. Drawings by Leonard Baskin, 1974., 37 cm. Illustrated.
    - A Passover Haggadah: the new Union Haggadah / edited by Herbert Bronstein; drawings by Leonard Baskin, 1975., 26 cm. Illustrated.
    - The humanist Haggadah / [Sherwin T. Wine.], 1979., 26 cm. Text only.
      Denomination: Humanistic Judaism.
    - Passover Haggadah: the feast of freedom = [Hagadah shel Pesa.h] / edited by Rachel Anne Rabinowicz; illustrated by Dan Reisinger, 1982., 24 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover Haggadah: the feast of freedom = [Hagadah shel Pesa.h] / edited by Rachel Anne Rabinowicz; illustrated by Dan Reisinger, 1982., 24 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / edited by Rachel Anne Rabinowicz; illustrated by Dan Reisinger, 1982., 24 cm. Illustrated.
    - [Hagadah shel Pesah] = Gates of freedom: a Passover Haggadah / [edited] by Chaim Stern; visual interpretations by Todd Siler; introduction by Eugene B. Borowitz, 1982., 26 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Passover Hagadah = [Hagadah shel Pesah] / Dov ben Khayyim, editor, 1983., 24 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: Egalitarian.
    - The shalom seders: three Haggadahs / compiled by New Jewish Agenda; introduction by Arthur Waskow; preface by Grace Paley, 1984., 26 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: New Jewish Agenda.
      Rainbow Seder was first used on April 4, 1969, the first anniversary of [Dr. Martin Luther] King's death and the third night of Passover by 300 €˜Jews for Urban Justice' and 100 Christians -pg. 8. The Seder of the Children of Abraham deals with the Israeli-Palestinian conflict. A Haggadah of Liberation deals with women's issues.
    - Haggadah for the liberated lamb / [text editor, Roberta Kalechofsky; original text, by Roberta Kalechofsky], 1985., 26 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: Vegetarianism.
    - San Diego women's Haggadah, 1986., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: Women.
    - A seder of the sisters of Sarah: a Holy Thursday and Passover feminist liturgy / created by Ronnie Levin and Diann Neu. Silver Spring, Md.: Women's Alliance for Theology, Ethics and Ritual, c1986, 1986., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: Feminism.
    - Haggadah for the liberated lamb / [text editor, Roberta Kalechofsky; original text, by Roberta Kalechofsky], 1988., 27 cm. Illustrated.
    - [Hagadah shel Pesah: lefi minhage ha-Sefaradim va-`adot ha-Mizrah] = The Sephardi Haggadah: with translation, commentary and complete guide to the laws of Pesah and the Seder / by Jonathan Cohen, 1989., 25 cm. Text only.
    - Haggadah: a celebration of freedom / by Martha Shelley; with Hebrew translations by Ilana Brody, 1997., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      A women's Haggadah. An original English text with some Hebrew.
    - Like an orange on a Seder plate: our lesbian Haggadah / Ruth Simkin, 1999., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      Denomination: Lesbian.
    - Lel she'elot: hagadah shel Pesah = A night of questions: a Passover haggadah / edited by Rabbi Joy Levitt, Rabbi Michael Strassfeld; illustrated by Jeffrey Schrier, 2000., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - Lel she'elot: hagadah shel Pesah = A night of questions: a Passover haggadah / edited by Rabbi Joy Levitt, Rabbi Michael Strassfeld; illustrated by Jeffrey Schrier, 2000., 23 cm. Illustrated.
  - Facsimile Subseries, 1200-1990, (34 items)
    Includes detailed reproductions of early as well as modern manuscripts editions. Usually illuminated, often with Biblical scenes, depictions of Passover ritual and objects, and midrashic stories. The Birds Head Haggadah (Haggadah q #4), from 13th century Germany, is a richly illuminated manuscript which is unique in its handling of human figures. While there are many depictions of human beings throughout the Haggadah, most are fitted with birds' heads instead of human heads. It is often speculated that the birds' heads were used in strict compliance to the biblical prohibition of graven images. Other fine examples of facsimiles of early illuminated texts are the Washington Haggadah (A-34 #18) and the Barcelona Haggadah (A-34 #17).
    In addition to facsimiles of early manuscripts, the Duke University Libraries also own a number of facsimile editions of more recent manuscripts. These include the Haggadah in Memory of the Holocaust (E ff#86), which links the memory of the Holocaust to the redemption from Egypt, and the Moss Haggadah (Haggadah f#26). Along with the exact reproductions of the manuscripts, most of the facsimile editions include introductory essays, or even entire volumes, describing and analyzing the Haggadah.
    - The Birds Head Haggada of the Bezalel National Art Museum in Jerusalem / Facsimile volume printed in collotype by Kunstanstalt Max Jaffé in Vienna, 13th Century., 29 cm. Illuminated.
    - The Barcelona Haggadah: an illuminated Passover compendium from 14th-Century Catalonia in facsimile (MS British Library Additional 14761) / edited by Jeremy Schonfield; with translations of poems and Targumim by Raphael Loewe; other translations by David Goldstein and Jeremy Schonfield; and contributions by Malachi Beit-Arié .., 14th Century., 27 cm. Illuminated.
    - The Kaufmann Haggadah, 14th Century., 27 cm. Illuminated.
      Facsimile was printed in Budapest, Hungary in 1957. Includes 14 full page miniatures, and a decorated text.
    - The Sarajevo Haggadah. Text by Cecil Roth, 14th Century., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Sarajevo Haggadah. Text by Cecil Roth, 14th Century., 23 cm. Illustrated.
      Facsimile was published in New York in 1966. English introduction by Cecil Roth. The Haggadah consists of 34 full-page miniatures, an illuminated Haggadah text, and hymns and Torah readings for the Passover week. Signed in 1609 by Giovanni Domenico, a church censor. Named because of its location in the Sarajevo Museum. This Haggadah was almost destroyed during the bombardment of Sarajevo in 1994 but was saved by two staff members of the demolished museum where it was housed.
    - The Washington Haggadah: a facsimile edition of an illuminated fifteenth-Century Hebrew manuscript at the Library of Congress / signed by Joel ben Simeon; edited by Myron M. Weinstein, 1478., 28 cm. Illuminated.
    - Die Darmstädter Pessach-Haggadah: codex orientalis 8 der Landesbibliothek zu Darmstadt aus dem vierzehnten jahrhundert / herausgegeben und erläutert von Bruno Italiener; unter mitwirkung von Aron Freimann, August L. Mayer und Adolf Schmidt; mit einer gesamtbibliographie der illustrierten Haggadah, 15th Century., 29-37 cm. Illuminated.
      Facsimile was published in Leipzig, Germany, 1927-28. Written by the scribe Israel ben Meir of Heidelberg. The illuminations reflect contemporary German architecture and dress.
    - The Rylands Haggadah: a medieval Sephardi masterpiece in facsimile: an illuminated Passover compendium from mid-14th-Century Catalonia in the collections of the John Rylands University Library of Manchester, with a commentary and a cycle of poems / [introduction, notes on the illuminations, transcription, and English translation by Raphael Loewe], 15th Century., 34 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Passover Haggadah of Gershom Cohen: printed at Prague, in the year 5287/1527, 1526., 18 cm. Illuminated.
    - The earliest illustrated Haggadah: printed by Gershom Cohen at Prague / discovered and described by Lazarus Goldschmidt, 1526., 29 cm. Illuminated.
    - The earliest illustrated Haggadah: printed by Gershom Cohen at Prague / discovered and described by Lazarus Goldschmidt, 1526., 29 cm. Illuminated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Prag 287 = The Passover Haggadah: Prague 1526, 1526., 32 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1526., 36 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Ashkenazi Haggadah: a Hebrew manuscript of the mid-15th Century from the collections of the British Library / written and illuminated by Joel ben Simeon, called Feibusch Ashkenazi; with a commentary attributed to Eleazar ben Judah of Worms; introduction, notes on the illuminations, transcription, and English translation by David Goldstein, 16th Century., 39 cm. Illuminated.
      Facsimile was printed in Tel Aviv, 1985. Additional artwork added by a different artist. Includes a transcription of the Hebrew as well as an English translation.
    - The Ashkenazi Haggadah: a Hebrew manuscript of the mid-15th Century from the collections of the British Library / written and illuminated by Joel ben Simeon called Feibusch Ashkenazi; with a commentary attributed to Eleazar ben Judah of Worms; introduction, notes on the illumination, transcription, and English translation by David Goldstein, 16th Century., 39 cm. Illuminated.
      Facsimile was printed in New York, 1985. Additional artwork added by a different artist. Includes a transcription of the Hebrew as well as an English translation.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, Venetsyah 369 = The Passover Haggadah, Venice 1609 / mavo me-et Betsal'el Narkis, 1609., 35 cm. Illustrated.
      Facsimile was printed in Jerusalem in 1974 The Venice Haggada of 1609: introduction (15 p.) inserted. ranslated by Juda-Arie Leon de Modena.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Ofenbakh 482 = The Passover Haggadah: Offenbach 1722, 1722., 32 cm. Illustrated.
      Facsimile was printed in Jerusalem in 1972. Originally published by Yisra'el ben Mosheh.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Ashkenaz, 489 (1729) = Pessach Haggadah: Ashkenaz, 1729., 1729., 31 cm. Illuminated.
    - Hagadat Moravyah = The Moravian Haggadah, 1737., 31 cm. Illuminated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Altona, Ashkenaz, 498 (1738) / katav ve-tsayar, Yosef ben David mi-Laypnik = Passover Haggadah: Altona, Germany, 1738 / scribe, illustrator Joseph ben David of Leipnik, 1738., 34 cm. Illustrated.
      Facsimile was published in Tel Aviv, 1987. Includes an abbreviation of the Zevah Pesah commentary by Isaac Abravanel as well as a short mystical commentary. Ashkenazi and Sephardi rites included. Includes a separate introduction in Hebrew and English.
    - Hagadat Kopenhagen 499: faksimilah = Copenhagen Haggadah: facsimile, 1739., 33 cm. Illuminated.
      Facsimile was printed in Tel Aviv, 1986. The Artist: Uri Pheibush [Philip Isac Levy] ... Introduction by Chaya Benjamin (Hebrew and English, [12] p.) inserted.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / [`orekh u-mehkar, Nahman Ran, `orekhet mishneh, Nivah Penai] = Passover Haggadah / [editor and research, Nachman Ran, assist. editor, Niva Panai], 1751., 28 x 329 cmfolded to 28 x 12 cm. Illustrated.